Klaven Jones

Brooklyn, NY
klavenjones.com

klavensjones@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/klaven-jones/

917-615-5646 @ github.com/klavenj

Motivated software engineer with two years experience in web development, and a strong curiosity for learning new software, programs, and frameworks. Hardworking, quick-learner, adept at translating needs and transforming client challenges into accessible digital solutions. Great at working with others, collaborating both with other team members and clients, to achieve desired outcomes.

Experience

Self-Employed Aug 2020 - Present

Freelance Web Developer - Brooklyn, NY

- Conduct work for upwards of 4 clients in industries including Electrical Engineering and Education; creating accessible and profit-driving user interfaces accessed by approximately 500+ people
- Collaborate with each client in order to gain a clear understanding of each brief, and design digital solutions that suit client needs and achieve client goals
- Develop, test, and launch web applications for new companies; leveraging programs and frameworks, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Node, balancing them to meet client expectations
- Create user interfaces for various screens sizes, using design tools such as Sketch, Figma, and Invision to enhance client's user experience

Miramom Mar 2019 - Aug 2020

Full-Stack Web Developer (Consultant) - Brooklyn, NY

- Worked as part of a team of 3 developers and designers; developing core framework for client-side of the web application through React to make it visually appealing, functional, and dynamic
- Used Node JS, Express, and PostgreSQL to build RESTful APIs as the company migrated from WordPress CMS; improving flexibility and scalability
- Assisted with hiring; building development team through interviewing new interns and performing evaluations of interns; improving progress toward company mission

Miramom Dec 2018 - Mar 2019

Full-Stack Web Developer (Intern) - Brooklyn, NY

- Redesigned company interface to align with company site modernization goal; conducting the bulk of work on user interface through Sketch
- Worked together with CEO to enhance company's existing WordPress legacy website, making it more up-to-date, and transforming it into a full-stack web application through React, Node, and Express
- Architected APIs featuring user authentication; storing, deleting, and updating data in the database

Volunteer Work

Floam 2020

Developer

- A platform that allows helps musical artists book recording studios.
- Implemented several features to the application using React Native, Expo, TypeScript, and NestJS

Projects

CODR blog

Designer & Developer

- Built web application that allows developers to post blog posts.
- Used React, Next.js, and Firebase

Seekr Application Tracker

Designer & Developer

- Built a web application that tracks job applications.
- Used React, Next.js, AWS, Serverless

Education

New York City College of Technology

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems

Udacity 2021

Cloud Developer Nanodegree

Certifications

Build Front-end Web Apps from Scratch 2018

Codecademy

Technical Skills

- HTML
- CSS/Sass
- JavaScript
- React & React Native
- NextJS
- TailwindCSS
- Bootstrap
- jQuery
- GitGithub

- Express
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- Firebase
- AWS
- NodeJS
- Package Managers (NPM, Yarn)
- Sanity.io
- WordPress

Core Competencies

- Teamwork
- Front-end Web Development
- Back-end Web Development
- Collaboration
- Interpersonal Skills
- Communication
- Problem Solving
- Design